GERSON GARRIDO

https://github.com/gersongams

Lima, Perú

(+51) 955000821 \diamond ggarridom23@gmail.com

CAREER SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 6 years of experience. Capable of working with a variety of web technologies and software solutions. Motivated team member who has experience diagnosing problems and developing effective solutions. Passionate about software and new technologies.

EDUCATION

National University of Engineering Mar 2013 - Jun 2018

BS. in Computer Science.

Hackspace Apr 2018 - Dec 2018

Scholarship on High Performance Technological Program by PRODUCE

University of Engineering and Technology Mar 2022 - Dec 2024

M.S. in Computer Science.

CERTIFICATIONS

Google Cloud - Associate Cloud Engineer

Amazon Web Services - Cloud Practitioner

MIT - MicroMasters Program inStatistics and Data Science

Udacity, (Frontend, Full-stack, React) Nanodegree Program

PROJECTS

Crime Analysis and Prediction of the City of Philadelphia

A project that compares multiple machine learning algorithms for the prevention and location of areas with high criminal probability

Development and implementation of an interactive platform to visualize social inequality in Peru

Interactive platform using open data and web technologies to show social differences in Peru.

Anime Music Trivia

Music game built with ReactJS, NodeJS, Serverless-framework, GraphQL and MongoDB as a database.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Languages Javascript, Typescript, Python, Golang.
Styling Libraries CSS, Sass, Less, Stylus, Styled-Components.

Frameworks & Libraries NodeJS, ReactJS, GraphQL, Apollo, GatsbyJS, NextJS.

Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB.
Software & Tools AWS, GCP, Docker, Cypress, Jest.

WORK EXPERIENCE

BREIN Oct 2020 - Act.

Sr. Software Engineer

· Build a system for sales and developed different applications for the company and marketing team

- · Develop a React Native application for Occupational Health and Safety.
- · Build a dashboard for metrics and sales predictions using React and ReCharts.
- · Implement services for a covid prevention system app.

Globant Jul 2019 - Oct 2020

Ssr. Software Engineer

- · Develop a web app for a machine learning system using React that combine different colors for every space of a house.
- · Maintain an ecommerce application with more than 1M daily sells.
- · Work and design web components for a cruise company using Angular.
- · Build a system with data grids for an investment company.

Chazki Apr 2019 - Jul 2019

Frontend Developer

- · Design and build a system to register all the drivers from the company.
- · Redesign the main website using ReactJS .

Krowdy Sep 2018 - Mar 2019

Full Stack Developer

- · Part of the team that built a HHRR System to handle different job applicants and job posts.
- · Built microservices using AWS lambda and NodeJS.

CodeCraft Aug 2018 - Jun 2019

Remote - Lead Developer

- · Design and build a web system for sales and a booking platform using React with firebase.
- · Built services using Apollo and GraphQL.
- · Develop an app to sell tickets using React Native.

Peru Hop Feb 2018 - Sep 2018

Full Stack Developer

- · Create web applications for purchases and reservations of a hotel chain.
- · Build a point of selling for restaurants.
- · Develop a check-in system for hostels of the company.
- · Maintain the main website of the company.

Uniclick Jul 2016 - Jan 2018

Frontend Developer

- · Built different websites and web applications for e-commerces.
- · Part of the team that build games using phaser.js.